<Composers>
	<Composer>
		<Name>Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart</Name>
		<Title>Don Giovanni</Title>
		<Year>1787</Year>
		<Location>Prague</Location>
		<Synopsis>Don Giovanni, a young, arrogant, and sexually promiscuous nobleman, abuses and outrages everyone else in the cast until he encounters something he cannot kill, beat up, dodge, or outwit.</Synopsis>
		<Link>https://youtu.be/hMvrR7YrRzA</Link>
	</Composer>
	<Composer>
		<Name>Georges Bizet</Name>
		<Title>Carmen</Title>
		<Year>1875</Year>
		<Location>Paris</Location>
		<Synopsis>Don Jose, a Spanish officer abandons his family, his duty, his virtue, his reason, and at last his soul in favor of his all-consuming desire to possess the beautiful traveler Carmen.</Synopsis>
		<Link>https://youtu.be/nvOWF1d3RwM</Link>
	</Composer>
	<Composer>
		<Name>Giuseppe Verdi</Name>
		<Title>Rigoletto</Title>
		<Year>1851</Year>
		<Location>Venice</Location>
		<Synopsis>Tragic story revolves around the licentious Duke of Mantua, his hunch-backed court jester Rigoletto and Rigoletto's beautiful daughter Gilda.</Synopsis>
		<Link>https://youtu.be/fYDI6MWkCW8</Link>
	</Composer>	
	<Composer>
		<Name>Ludwig van Beethoven</Name>
		<Title>Symphony No. 9</Title>
		<Year>1824</Year>
		<Location>Vienna</Location>
		<Synopsis>His final complete symphony and the first example of a major composer using voices.The words are sung during the final (4th) movement of the symphony by four vocal soloists and a chorus. They were taken from the "Ode to Joy", a poem written by Friedrich Schiller in 1785 and revised in 1803.</Synopsis>
		<Link>https://youtu.be/rOjHhS5MtvA</Link>
	</Composer>	
	<Composer>
		<Name>Richard Wagner</Name>
		<Title>Tristan und Isolde</Title>
		<Year>1865</Year>
		<Location>Munich</Location>
		<Synopsis>In a Middle Ages legend, in Cornwall, England, an Irish Princess, Isolde, is on board a ship from Ireland to Cornwall, as she marries King Marke who governs Cornwall. She is escorted by Tristan, the King's loyalist and his nephew.</Synopsis>
		<Link>https://youtu.be/IdjFBW-S3z0</Link>
	</Composer>	
	<Composer>
		<Name>Pyotr Ilyich Tchaikovsky</Name>
		<Title>Swan Lake</Title>
		<Year>1877</Year>
		<Location>Moscow</Location>
		<Synopsis>Timeless love story that mixes magic, tragedy, and romance into four acts. It features Prince Siegfried and a lovely swan princess named Odette. Under the spell of a sorcerer, Odette spends her days as a swan swimming on a lake of tears and her nights in her beautiful human form.</Synopsis>
		<Link>https://youtu.be/9rJoB7y6Ncs</Link>
	</Composer>	
	<Composer>
		<Name>Johann Sebastian Bach</Name>
		<Title>Goldberg Variations</Title>
		<Year>1741</Year>
		<Location>Leipzig</Location>
		<Synopsis>Musical composition for harpsichord, consisting of an aria and a set of 30 variations.</Synopsis>
		<Link>https://youtu.be/Cwas_7H5KUs</Link>
	</Composer>	
	<Composer>
		<Name>Frédéric François Chopin</Name>
		<Title>The Revolutionary Etude</Title>
		<Year>1831</Year>
		<Location>Paris</Location>
		<Synopsis>Dedicated to his dear Hungarian companion, Franz Liszt, this piece tells the story of pain and struggle during the Polish November Uprising as a protest against the Bolshevik authorities.</Synopsis>
		<Link>https://youtu.be/g1uLrHq9TDg</Link>
	</Composer>	
	<Composer>
		<Name>Richard Strauss</Name>
		<Title>Salome</Title>
		<Year>1905</Year>
		<Location>Dresden</Location>
		<Synopsis>The combination of the Christian biblical theme, the erotic and the murderous, which so attracted Wilde to the tale, shocked ballet audiences from its first appearance.</Synopsis>
		<Link>https://youtu.be/kInyoCPyFb0</Link>
	</Composer>	
	<Composer>
		<Name>Franz Joseph Haydn</Name>
		<Title>London Symphony 104</Title>
		<Year>1795</Year>
		<Location>London</Location>
		<Synopsis>This was Haydn’s last symphony in 4 movements: Adagio –Allegro,Andante, Menuetto and Trio: Allegro, and Finale: Spiritoso.</Synopsis>
		<Link>https://youtu.be/OitPLIowJ70</Link>
	</Composer>	
	<Composer>
		<Name>Igor Fyodorovich Stravinsky</Name>
		<Title>The Rite of Spring</Title>
		<Year>1913</Year>
		<Location>Paris</Location>
		<Synopsis>This piece transformed the way in which subsequent composers thought about rhythmic structureand was largely responsible for Stravinsky's enduring reputation as a musical revolutionary who pushed the boundaries of musical design.</Synopsis>
		<Link>https://youtu.be/EkwqPJZe8ms</Link>
	</Composer>		
	<Composer>
		<Name>Antonín Dvorák</Name>
		<Title>Rusulka</Title>
		<Year>1901</Year>
		<Location>Prague</Location>
		<Synopsis>The most popular and successful Czech opera, Rusalka tells the story of an immortal water nymph from Slavic Mythology who falls in love with a prince and yearns to become human.</Synopsis>
		<Link>https://youtu.be/huZAJ2ZbGnQ</Link>
	</Composer>
	<Composer>
		<Name>Jacopo Peri</Name>
		<Title>Euridice</Title>
		<Year>1600</Year>
		<Location>Florence</Location>
		<Synopsis>Euridice was created for the marriage of King Henry IV of France and Maria de Medici. The composition is typically considered to be the second work of modern opera, and the first such musical drama to survive to the present day.</Synopsis>
		<Link>https://youtu.be/TGSaKrcL0eg</Link>
	</Composer>
	<Composer>
		<Name>Georg Friederich Händel</Name>
		<Title>Messiah</Title>
		<Year>1742</Year>
		<Location>Dublin</Location>
		<Synopsis>Händel's most famous work, the oratorio Messiah with its "Hallelujah" chorus is among the most popular works in choral music and has become a centerpiece of the Christmas season.</Synopsis>
		<Link>https://youtu.be/bR0cEOTpYSk</Link>
	</Composer>
	<Composer>
		<Name>Antonio Salieri</Name>
		<Title>Falstaff</Title>
		<Year>1799</Year>
		<Location>Vienna</Location>
		<Synopsis>Falstaff, ossia Le tre burle (Falstaff, or The Three Jokes) is a dramma giocoso in two acts based on William Shakespeare's The Merry Wives of Windsor, notable for a general compression and streamlining of the original plot.</Synopsis>
		<Link>https://youtu.be/nO5x7XfXzvM</Link>
	</Composer>
	<Composer>
		<Name>Giaochino Rossini</Name>
		<Title>The Barber of Seville</Title>
		<Year>1816</Year>
		<Location>Rome</Location>
		<Synopsis>Rossini's opera recounts the events of the first of the three plays by French playwright Pierre Beaumarchais that revolve around the clever and enterprising character named Figaro, the barber of the title.</Synopsis>
		<Link>https://youtu.be/gDbBhzIcYj4</Link>
	</Composer>
	<Composer>
		<Name>Francesca Caccini</Name>
		<Title>La liberazione di Ruggiero</Title>
		<Year>1625</Year>
		<Location>Florence</Location>
		<Synopsis>A comic opera in four scenes, La liberazione di Ruggiero dall'isola d'Alcina (The Liberation of Ruggiero from the island of Alcina) is the first opera written by a woman and was long considered to be the first Italian opera to be performed outside of Italy.</Synopsis>
		<Link>https://youtu.be/4H0-XKnFhuo</Link>
	</Composer>
	<Composer>
		<Name>Giacomo Puccini</Name>
		<Title>Madama Butterfly</Title>
		<Year>1904</Year>
		<Location>Milan</Location>
		<Synopsis>Despite its status as a staple of the operatic world, Puccini's original two-act composition was poorly received. After a substantial rewrite, his three-act version of the tragic tale of Cio-cio-san and Lt. BF Pinkerton remains one of most performed (and most popular) operas of all time.</Synopsis>
		<Link>https://youtu.be/IYrbdiee9SU</Link>
	</Composer>
	<Composer>
		<Name>Jean-Baptiste Lully</Name>
		<Title>Ballet Royal de la Nuit</Title>
		<Year>1653</Year>
		<Location>Paris</Location>
		<Synopsis>A 13-hour epic in four "watches", this opera-ballet starred the 14-year-old King Louis XIV, appearing with the coming of the day as the sun god Apollo— one of his many personifications as the rising sun, emphasizing the power of the monarchy and its closeness to the divine.</Synopsis>
		<Link>https://youtu.be/hgoouzWghFg</Link>
	</Composer>
	<Composer>
		<Name>Amy Marcy Cheney Beach</Name>
		<Title>Gaelic Symphony</Title>
		<Year>1896</Year>
		<Location>Boston</Location>
		<Synopsis>The first symphony composed and published by a female American composer, Gaelic Symphony debuted to public and journalistic acclaim. Beach drew inspiration for her large orchestral work from simple old English, Irish, and Scottish melodies.</Synopsis>
		<Link>https://youtu.be/1iklcodWfLk</Link>
	</Composer>	
</Composers>